A Guide to the Papers of John Randolph of Roanoke, 1781-1860, [n.d.]
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I: Letters and Documents
  - John Randolph to Elizabeth Tucker Coalter and Betty Tucker Coalter, 1812 December 10--1824 April 25, ALSs, 68 pp. on 68 l.; copies in unidentified hand. #3400. (Box-folder 3:96)
    1812 December 10 to Fanny Bland C[oalter]; 1821 June 12 to Betty Tucker; 1821 July 29 to Betty Tucker; 1822 January 27 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1822 February 5 to "My Dear Child"; 1822 February 18 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1822 February 19 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; to "My Dear Girls"; 1822 December 9 to "My Dear Child"; 1822 December 15 to "My Dear Child"; 1822 December 29 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1822 January 11 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1822 January 19 to unidentified recipient; 1822 January 21 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1822 January 30 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1823 February 26 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1823 February 14 to E[lizabeth] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1823 February 19 to E[lizabeth] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1823 August 9 to "My Dear Child"; 1823 August 23 to unidentified recipient; 1823 September 26 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1823 October 23 to "My Dear Child"; 1824 January 31 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1824 February 17 to B[etty] T[ucker Coalter]; 1824 February 29 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1824 March 6 to Betty T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1824 March 12 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1824 March 20 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1824 March 21 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1824 April 25 to B[etty] T[ucker] C[oalter]; 1824 March 26 to Mrs. [Delia] Bryan (typescript).
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1812 December 15, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 3:97)
  - [John Randolph] to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1812 December 15, AL, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 3:98)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1812 December 23, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 3:99)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to [James Mercer Garnett], 1812 December 29, ANS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 3:100)
  - B[enjamin] W[atkins] L[eigh] to John Randolph, [ca. 1812- 1815], ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; #3339. (Box-folder 3:101)
    Mentions, and presumably written during, the War of 1812.
  - [John Randolph] to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1813 January 6, AL, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:1)
  - John St. George Randolph to John Randolph, 1813 January 8, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3400. (Box-folder 4:2)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1813 January 12, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:3)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1813 January 19, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:4)
  - John St. George Randolph to John Randolph, 1813 January 20, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with separate address leaf; docketed. Address leaf torn; Letter torn and taped together; Fragile. #3400. (Box-folder 4:5)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1813 January 22, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:6)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1813 January 26, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:7)
  - [John Randolph] to [James Mercer Garnett], 1813 February 4, AL, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:8)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to [James Mercer Garnett], 1813 February 16, ANS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:9)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1813 February 23, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 4:10)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1813 February 27, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1813 March 1, ALS, 2 pp.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Richmond VA, March [?]. #1883. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1813 March 2, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:13)
  - Fanny Bland Coalter to John Randolph, 1813 March 21, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Richmond VA, March 22. #3400. (Box-folder 4:14)
    Note on address leaf that this letter is the last Fanny wrote to John Randolph.
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1813 March 25., ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed. (Box-folder 4:15)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1813 April 16, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:16)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1813 April 22., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 4:17)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1813 May 11, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:18)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1813 May 15, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Charlotte [Court House, Va.], May 24. #1883. (Box-folder 4:19)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1813 May 20, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Richmond VA, May 21. #1883. (Box-folder 4:20)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1813 May 24, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:21)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1813 June 13., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. #3677. (Box-folder 4:22)
  - John Randolph to Joseph Delaplaine, 1813 June 13, ALS, 1 p. #3598. (Box-folder 4:23)
  - J[udith] Randolph to John Randolph, 1813 June 13, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #3400. (Box-folder 4:24)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1813 June 25, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:25)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1813 June 2[9], ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:26)
    Letter continued on 1813 July 4.
  - John St. George Randolph to John Randolph, 1813 July [9], ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. Letter brittle and discolored along old fold, and has an undated continuation in pencil on the verso. #3400. (Box-folder 4:27)
  - J[udith] Randolph to John Randolph, [1813] July 10, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #3400. (Box-folder 4:28)
  - J[udith] Randolph to John Randolph, 1813 July 15, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #3400. (Box-folder 4:29)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1813 July 20, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 4:30)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1813 July 24, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; postmarked Charlotte [Court House, Va.], July 26. #1883. (Box-folder 4:31)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1813 July 25., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; postmarked Charlotte Court House VA, July 20. #3677. (Box-folder 4:32)
  - John St. George Randolph to [John Randolph], 1813 July-, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. #3400. (Box-folder 4:33)
  - John St. G[eorge Randolph] to [John Randolph], 1813 August 3, ALS, 1 p. Partial signature because of brittle paper. #3400. (Box-folder 4:34)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1813 August 5, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:35)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1813 August 7, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; postmarked Charlotte [Court House], August 9. #1883. (Box-folder 4:36)
  - John Randolph to Charles Goldsborough, 1813 August 7, ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l.; includes typed transcription. #6489. (Box-folder 4:37)
  - John St. George Randolph to John Randolph, 1813 August 14, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. #3400. (Box-folder 4:38)
  - John Coalter to John Randolph, 1813 August 21, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #3400. (Box-folder 4:39)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1813 August 22., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; postmarked Charlotte Court House VA, August 23. #3677. (Box-folder 4:40)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1813 August 24, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:41)
  - John St. George Randolph to John Randolph, 1813 September 3, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. #3400. (Box-folder 4:42)
  - J[udith] Randolph to John Randolph, 1813 September 11, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #3400. (Box-folder 4:43)
  - John Randolph to Benjamin Watkins Leigh, 1813 September 25, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #8716-a. (Box-folder 4:44)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1813 October 5, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:45)
  - John St. George Randolph to John Randolph, 1813 October 8, ALS, 1 p. #3400. (Box-folder 4:46)
  - J[udith] Randolph to John Randolph, 1813 October 15, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. #3400. (Box-folder 4:47)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1813 October 17, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:48)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1813 November 18, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed; postmarked Richmond, VA, Novmber 18. In bound volume (Box 8), page 20; includes typed transcription that incorrectly states letter was written on the 15th. #3677. (Box-folder 4:49)
  - John Randolph to Tudor [Randolph], 1813 December 13, L, 6 pp. on 3 l.; Typed copy. #49. (Box-folder 4:50)
    Contains an autobiographical account of his life to his nephew Tudor Randolph.
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1813 December 18, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; blank portion of last page torn away; #1883. (Box-folder 4:51)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1813 December 31, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Richmond VA, January 5. #1883. (Box-folder 4:52)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1814 January 25, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:53)
  - John Randolph to John Lowell, 1814 January 25, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed; postmarked Richmond VA, January [2]5. #9371-a. (Box-folder 4:54)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1814 January 28., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; postmarked Richmond VA, January 28. #3677. (Box-folder 4:55)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1814 February 2., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf with partial wax seal; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 4:56)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1814 February 8, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:57)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1814 February 11, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:58)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1814 February 14, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:59)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1814 February 18, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Bottom left hand corner torn away, affecting text; #1883. (Box-folder 4:60)
  - John Randolph to Charles Harris, 1814 February 23, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; postmarked, February [?]. #6489. (Box-folder 4:61)
  - John Randolph to Thomas M. Forman, 1814 February 24, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Richmond VA, February 24. #3440-a. (Box-folder 4:62)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer Garnett], 1814 February 2[8], ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:63)
  - John Brockenbrough to [James Mercer Garnett], 1814 March 8, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:64)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1814 March 20, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 4:65)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1814 March 29, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:66)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1814 April 4., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 4:67)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1814 April 8, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:68)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to Dr. R[ichard] S[tanford], 1814 April 9, ALS, copy, 2 pp. on 1 l.; 19th century copy in unidentified hand; #1883. (Box-folder 4:69)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to [Richard] Stanford, 1814 April 11, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:70)
  - John St. George Randolph to John Randolph, 1814 April 19, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed. (Box-folder 4:71)
    Note on address leaf that the letter was sent after St. George became mad, and that the letter was found in St. George's desk at Bizarre. Also contains an unsigned enclosure in another's handwriting, and may possibly be written by John Randolph.
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1814 May 9, ALS, 6 pp. on 3 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:72)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1814 May 14, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:73)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1814 May 25, ALS, 6 pp. on 3 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:74)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to [Judith] Randolph, 1814 May 30, ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l.; with separate address leaf, with partial wax seal and later postscript; postmarked Charlotte Court House, June 21. #3400. (Box-folder 4:75)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1814 June 2., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; postmarked Charlotte Court House VA. #3677. (Box-folder 4:76)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1814 June 19, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:77)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1814 July 26-28., ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal. #3677. (Box-folder 4:78)
  - John Randolph to David Parish, 1814 July 28, ALS, 1 p.; photostat, location of original unknown. #3410. (Box-folder 4:79)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1814 July 29, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; #1883. (Box-folder 4:80)
  - J[udith] Randolph to John Randolph, 1814 August 1, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with remnants of wax seal. #3400. (Box-folder 4:81)
  - B[enjamin] W[atkins] Leigh to [John Randolph], 1814 September 1, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Concerning the survey of Richmond, Virginia for defense against attack. #3339. (Box-folder 4:82)
  - B[enjamin] W[atkins] Leigh to John Randolph, 1814 September 1, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. Concerning evaluating Richmond's defenses in case of attack. #3339. (Box-folder 4:83)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1814 September 23., ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 4:84)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer Garnett], 1814 October 1, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:85)
  - John Randolph to R[ichard] Stanford, 1814 October 13, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Baltimore MD, October 13. #3339. (Box-folder 4:86)
  - John Randolph to [Anne Cary Randolph Morris], 1814 October 31, ALS, 14 pp. on 13 l.; 19th century copy in unidentified hand. #10652. (Box-folder 4:87)
    In a widely circulated and copied letter concerning the scandal at Bizarre, Randolph writes to Anne Cary Randolph Morris accusing her of the deaths of her child and her lover, Richard Randolph, John Randolph's brother. Anne Cary Randolph Morris refuted the charges in an 1815 January 16 letter (q.v.) to Randolph.
  - John Randolph to Richard Stanford, 1814 November 15, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; postmarked New York NY, November 15. #3339. (Box-folder 4:88)
  - John Randolph to David Parish, 1814 November 28, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #4319-b. (Box-folder 4:89)
  - John Randolph to Richard Stanford, 1814 December 2, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Philadelphia PA, December 2. #3339. (Box-folder 4:90)
    Notes on address leaf in Randolph's? hand refer to the scandal at Bizarre, Richard Randolph, Theodorick Randolph, and Anne Cary Randolph Morris. "Nothing but my utter incredulity that my poor brother could perpetrate so foul a deed as incest, seduction & murder could have blinded me to the Truth. The Story he told me about poor The, our brother, I knew to be false, but whilst his word was his oath in all matters that might advantage him or disadvantage his enemy he over simpled a white lie to serve friend or foe[.] The singular benevolence of his character deceived himself & every body else. I who had as lief taken Tartaric forced my tastes[?] and pretended to like Randolph Harrison's wretched"
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, [ca. 1814 December 8?]., ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Philadelphia PA, December 8. #3677. (Box-folder 4:91)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1814 December 27., ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; postmarked Philadelphia PA. #3677. (Box-folder 4:92)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to Richard Stanford, 1815 January 1, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Philadelphia PA. #1883. (Box-folder 4:93)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1815 January 2., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed; postmark illegible. #3677. (Box-folder 4:94)
  - John Randolph to Mrs. [John Randolph] Clay, 1815 January 14, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf. #5661-a. (Box-folder 4:95)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1815 January 14, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:96)
  - Anne Cary [Randolph] Morris to [John Randolph], 1815 January 16, ALS, 7 pp. on 2 l.; 19th century extract in unidentified hand. #10652. (Box-folder 4:97)
    Morris denies the charges made by John Randolph in his letter of 1814 October 31 (q.v.), concerning the scandal at Bizarre.
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1815 January 19, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:98)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1815 January 23, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:99)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1815 February 1, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:100)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1815 February 4., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with separate address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed; postmarked February [?]. #3677. (Box-folder 4:101)
  - [John Randolph] to [James Mercer Garnett], 1815 February 10, AL, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:102)
  - John Randolph to Harry Heth, 1815 March 29, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed; silked. #38-114. (Box-folder 4:103)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1815 April 1[8]?., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 4:104)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1815 May 20, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Richmond VA, May [?]. #1883. (Box-folder 4:105)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1815 May 27, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 4:106)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1815 May 31, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 4:107)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to J[ames] M[ercer] Garnett, 1815 July 3, ALS, 1 p.; with address on verso; postmarked Fredricksburg VA, July 19. #1883. (Box-folder 4:108)
  - John Randolph to Henry Middleton Rutledge, 1815 July 24, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; with typescript copy; #6489. (Box-folder 4:109)
  - James Mercer Garnett to John Randolph, 1815 July 25, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 4:110)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1815 September 7, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; postmarked Richmond VA, September 15. #1883. (Box-folder 4:111)
  - John Randolph to David Parish, 1815 September 18, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed. #4319-a. (Box-folder 4:112)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1815 October 7., ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 4:113)
  - John Randolph to David Parish, 1815 October 30, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed. #4319-a. (Box-folder 4:114)
  - John St. George Randolph to John Randolph, 1815 November 10, ALS, 1 p.; with address on verso. #3400. (Box-folder 4:115)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1816 January 12, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:116)
  - John Randolph to Robert G. Harris, 1816 January 13, ALS, 1 p. #6564. (Box-folder 4:117)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1816 January 15, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:118)
  - J[ohn] R[andolph] to David Parish, 181[6] January 15, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed. #4319-a. (Box-folder 4:119)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer] Garnett, 1816 January 16, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l.; with attached partial address leaf, with postscript dated January 17; #1883. (Box-folder 4:120)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1816 January 16, ANS, 1 p. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; #1883. (Box-folder 4:121)
    Enclosures: a copy of the note (ANS, 1 p. on 1 l.) and an additional note (ANS, 1 p. on 1 l.) asking Garnett to burn or lock up the letter.
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer] Garnett, 3 o'clock [ca. 1816 January 16], ANS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:122)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1816 January 21, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 4:123)
  - John Randolph to David Parish, 181[6] January 23, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; docketed. #4319-a. (Box-folder 4:124)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1816 January 30, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 4:125)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1816 January 30., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. #3677. (Box-folder 4:126)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1816 January 31, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:1)
  - John Randolph, letter cover addressed to Miss Fanny Coalter, 1816 February 1, AD, 1 p.; with partial wax seal. #4707. (Box-folder 5:2)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1816 February 2, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; #1883. (Box-folder 5:3)
  - John Randolph to David Parish, 1816 February 3, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. #4319-a. (Box-folder 5:4)
    Concerning Theodorick Tudor Randolph's (1796- 1815 August 18) death and containing the inscription on his gravestone.
  - John Randolph to H[armanus] Bleecker, 1816 February 4., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. #3677. (Box-folder 5:5)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1816 February 4, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:6)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1816 February 4, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:7)
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1816 February 11, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:8)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1816 February 12, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; docketed; #1883. (Box-folder 5:9)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1816 February 15, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:10)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1816 March 12., ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal; docketed. #3677. (Box-folder 5:11)
  - John Randolph to Harmanus Bleecker, 1816 March 21., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with separate address leaf, with wax seal; docketed; postmark illegible. #3677. (Box-folder 5:12)
  - John Randolph to David Parish, 1816 April 2, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf, with partial wax seal; docketed; postmark illegible. #9953-b. (Box-folder 5:13)
  - John Randolph to [Harmanus Bleecker], 1816 April 10, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. #3677. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Mentions his disdain for poetry although occasionally "tak[ing] up Milton and Shakespeare, "but [he] read[s] very little of any thing. Dr. Johnson never read books throughout & [he] improve[s] upon his practice by not reading them at all."
  - John Randolph to James Mercer Garnett, 1816 April 16, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:15)
  - James Mercer Garnett to [John Randolph], 1816 April 19, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:16)
  - John Randolph to David Parish, [1816] April 22, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. With typescript copy. #6489. (Box-folder 5:17)
  - John Randolph to [James Mercer Garnett], 1816 April 23, ALS, 1 p.; #1883. (Box-folder 5:18)
  - Daniel Webster to John Randolph, [1816 April 30], AN, 1 p.; with attached address leaf, with wax seal. Also contains unrelated envelope addressed to Peyton A. Southall in care of the Honorable Waddy Thompson. #3339. (Box-folder 5:19)